Konstantinos Patlatzoglou, Ph.D.

🛂 Thessaloniki, Greece

4 26/02/1992

+30 6945940517

★ konspatl@gmail.com

konspatl.github.io

in linkedin.com/in/konspatl/

github.com/konspatl

ORCID:0000-0002-5888-8490

About

Computer scientist with a background in AI, Neuroscience and Biomedical Engineering. During the past 5+ years, my experience has focused on research and development of machine learning models for neurophysiological signal analysis. Currently, I'm interested in exploring machine learning methods for scientific discovery and clinical applications.

Experience

2017 – 2022 **Univers**

- University of Kent Machine Learning Researcher
 - Researched and developed deep learning-based EEG models for automated, end-to-end, real-time monitoring of the depth of anesthesia.
 - Collaborated with an interdisciplinary team of computer scientists, neuroscientists, and clinicians.
 - Published and presented research results in scientific conferences, demonstrating a novel convolutional neural network for EEG analysis that achieved generalized performance across multiple anesthetic paradigms.

Skills: • Python (*Tensorflow*) • EEG Analysis (*MNE*) • Digital Signal Processing

• Machine Learning • Deep Learning • Research Methods • Project Management

2017 - 2021

- **University of Kent Teaching Assistant**
 - Prepared and taught undergraduate modules in Computer Science through lab supervision and assistance of students in groups of ~ 20 (Part time).
 - Marked and provided feedback on student assignments and term projects

Skills: • Teaching • Written and Spoken Communication

Education

2017 – 2022 **Ph.D. in Computer Science** - University of Kent

Thesis title: Deep Learning for Electrophysiological Investigation and Estimation of Anesthetic-Induced Unconsciousness.

2015 – 2016 M.Sc. in Sound and Music Computing - Universitat Pompeu Fabra

Grade: 8.53/10

Thesis title: Neural and Music Correlates of Music-Evoked Emotions.

2010 – 2015 **B.Sc. in Informatics** - Aristotle University of Thessaloniki

Grade: 8.69/10 (First Class Honours)

Thesis title: A study of causal interactions during music listening based on EEG signals using estimates of nonlinear correlations.

Areas of Proficiency

- Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- NeuroInformatics and Computational Neuroscience

- Digital Signal Processing
- Teaching
- · Sound and Music Perception and Cognition

Skills

Languages Greek (*Native*), English (*Proficiency*)

Coding Python, Java, Matlab, C, SQL

ML Libraries Scikit-learn, Tensorflow, Keras

> Misc. MS Office, LTEX, Unix Shell, Git, Slurm

Activities and Interests

- Biomedical Engineering Cognitive Science and Psychology
- Music Perception and Cognition

- Evolutionary Biology
- Massive Open Online Courses (MOOCs)
- Music Composition and Production

Teaching

Introduction to Object-Oriented Programming 2017 - 2021

Advanced Object-Oriented Programming 2017 - 2019

Data Structures and Algorithms 2019 - 2021

Agile Development and Software Security 2019 - 2020

2018 - 2020 Computing Theory and Concurrent Programming

Research Publications

- Patlatzoglou, K. (2022). Deep learning for electrophysiological investigation and estimation of anesthetic-induced unconsciousness (Doctoral dissertation, University of Kent,). Retrieved from
- Patlatzoglou, K., Chennu, S., Gosseries, O., Bonhomme, V., Wolff, A., & Laureys, S. (2020). Generalized Prediction of Unconsciousness during Propofol Anesthesia using 3D Convolutional Neural Networks. In 2020 42nd annual international conference of the ieee engineering in medicine & biology society (embc) (Vol. 2020-July, pp. 134-137). Odoi:10.1109/EMBC44109.2020.9175324
- Patlatzoglou, K., Chennu, S., Boly, M., Noirhomme, Q., Bonhomme, V., Brichant, J.-F., ... Laureys, S. (2018). Deep Neural Networks for Automatic Classification of Anesthetic-Induced Unconsciousness. In Lecture notes in computer science (including subseries lecture notes in artificial intelligence and lecture notes in bioinformatics) (Vol. 11309 LNAI, pp. 216–225). 🔗 doi:10.1007/978-3-030-05587-5_21

Grants and Awards

2017 - 2020 Postgraduate research scholarship grant awarded by the University of Kent

Grants and Awards (continued)

2017 – 2021 Conference and summer school attendance grants awarded by the University of Kent

Conferences and Workshops

Sep 2020	Pattern Recognition in Neuroimaging (PRNI) Summer School, Vienna, Austria
Jul 2020	42 nd Annual International Conference of the IEEE Engineering in Medicine and Biology Society (EMBC), Montreal, Canada
	Invited Talk: Generalized Prediction of Unconsciousness during Propofol Anesthesia using 3D Convolutional Neural Networks
May 2020	Brain, Cognition, Emotion and Music (BCEM) Conference, Kent, UK
Nov 2019	Studying Consciousness in the Electrical Brain - Luminous Workshop, Oxford, UK Poster Presentation: Classification and Regression Analysis of Anesthetic States using Electroencephalography and Deep Learning
Jul 2019	3 rd International Summer School on Deep Learning, Warshaw, Poland
Jun 2019	1 st Interdisciplinary Research on Brain Network Dynamics (Brandy) Summer School, Terzolas, Italy
Dec 2018	11 th International Conference on Brain Informatics, Arlington, Texas, US
	Invited Talk: Deep Neural Networks for Automatic Classification of Anesthetic-Induced Unconsciousness
Sep 2018	Complex Systems Society (CCS) Conference, Thessaloniki, Greece
	Invited Talk: Classification Analysis of Levels of Consciousness under Anesthesia, using Electroencephalography and Deep Learning Techniques
Sep 2017	International Symposium on Performance Science (ISPS), Reykjavik, Iceland
	Poster Presentation: Neural and Music Correlates of Music-Evoked Emotions